Yuya Tinnefeld

Cloud DevOps Engineer

SUMMARY/OBJECTIVE

Passionate Software Engineer with 4+ years of experience in data engineering and backend systems. Skilled at writing clear, concise code that is easy to maintain and troubleshoot. Experienced in working with both small and large teams across multiple projects and companies. I always loved the tickle of excitement that you get, when you jump heads on into a new project. While diving deeper into this versatile technology, it just amazes me over and over again.

Phone: (+49) 1797908144

Email: yuyatinnefeld@gmail.com

Address: Düsseldorf

github.com/yuyatinnefeld

SKILLS

Programming Languages

Python, Go, Shell, SQL, Scala

Cloud Provider

GCP, AWS, Snowflake

DevOps

Kubernetes, Docker, Terraform, Gitlab, Github, ArgoCD, Flux, Prometheus, Grafana

Data Engineering / Big Data

PostgreSQL, MySQL, BigQuery, Spark, Hadoop, Airflow, Kafka, MongoDB, ScyllaDB

LANGUAGE SKILLS

Japanese (Native Language) German (Fluent, C2) English (Business, C1)

CERTIFICATIONS/LICENSES

HashiCorp Terraform HashiCorp Vault

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Cloud DevOps Engineer // REWE digital, Cologne 07/2021 - Today

- DevOps Integration (Docker, k8s, Gitlab CI, Terraform)
- Data Pipeline Development (Spark, Dataproc, Airflow)
- Application Development (FastAPI, Cloud Run, GCE)
- Service Migration from On-Premise on GCP

Marketing Data Analyst & Engineer // Publics Media, Düsseldorf 03/2018 - 06/2021

- Data Engineering (Flask, Pandas, Selenium)
- Data Analysis & Tracking (GA, BigQuery, Jupyter)
- Projekt Management, Workshops, Consulting

Web Analyst & SEO // RTL Interactive, Cologne 09/2017 - 02/2018

- Web Analytics (Google Analytics)
- Search Engine Optimization (On- and Off Page)

Student Trainee & Internship // network.publishing, Cologne 12/2016 - 08/2017

- Web Analytics (Google Analytics)
- Data Warehouse & Data Mining

ECommerce Startup CEO & CTO // Wanamour, Cologne

11/2014 - 06/2022

- Management
- Web Development & Web Design
- Marketing

EDUCATION

University of applied sciences Bonn-Rhein-Sieg

B.Sc. Business information systems

09/2013 - 08/2017

Focus area: Business Intelligence (Data-Warehouse, Data Mining, Predictive Analysis, Decision Support System